Hello friends, I am Mohammad Arshad,
welcome to my YouTube channel.
Friends, today I am going to tell you all about Health Advantage,
a popular health insurance plan from ICICI Lombard.
First, we will understand the
eligibility criteria and features of this plan.
After that, we will also understand the optional advances given in this plan.
Finally, we will also understand the waiting period. So,
friends, to understand this plan better, do
not skip this video at all
and watch it till the end. So, let's
start.
First, let's
understand the eligibility criteria and features of this plan.
If we talk about the entry age in this plan, then
this plan can be taken by a person between the age of 18 years to 65 years.
If we
talk about dependent children in this plan, then children between the age of 911 days to
25 years can be covered.
If we talk about the policy type, then
this plan can be taken as an individual
or a family floater.
If we talk about the maximum family size, then
This plan can be availed for two adults plus three children.
Talking about the policy tenure, this plan can also be availed by paying premium for one, two or three years
together.
Paying 2 years' premium together gives you a discount of 7.5% and paying 3 years'
premium together gives you a
discount of 10%. Talking about the plan type,
this is the Apex Plus plan. I
would like to tell you that there are many other versions of Health Advantage,
but this is its
latest version. Talking about time shot,
time shot ranging from ₹5 lakh to ₹3 crore
is available in this plan.
Talking about room rent in this plan, you
can take any room. Talking about pre and post hospitalization expenses in this plan,
it is 60 and 180 days. Talking about road ambulance in this plan,
it is 1 per time
sod with a maximum limit of ₹10,000 per
hospital. Talking about domestic air ambulance in this plan,
it is covered up
to some shd.  If we talk about day care procedures, then
all day care is covered in this plan.
If we talk about AYUSH treatment, then it is also
covered up to 50% off sum. If we talk about domiciliary hospital, then
it is also
covered up to 50% off sum. For this, a minimum treatment of 10 days is required. If we talk about organ donor expenses, then it is also covered up to 50%
off sum. If we talk about home care treatment, then
it is covered up to 50% off sum. If we talk about animal bite, then it is covered up to
50% off sum. If we talk about rheumatic surgery, then it
is covered up to 50% off sum. If we
talk about health checkup in this plan, then you can get it done from day one. If we talk about
10000, then it
is available on cashless basis. If we
talk about restoration benefit in this plan, then it is
100% for any illness.
Talking about the cumulative bonus, it
is 20% per time sum and goes up to a maximum of 100%.
If we talk about the benefits in this plan, then if the
hospitalization is of 10 days or more,
you will be given a lump sum of ₹2,000,000.
Friends, in this plan, you
also get worldwide coverage if you have taken a term plan of ₹25 lakh or
more. Friends,
now let's understand the optional benefits in this plan.
For this, you
can see the table given on the screen. First, there is the
maternity benefit, which can be
availed for a maximum of three deliveries. 10% per
basic time sum, whose limit is ₹1 lakh.
Friends, if you pay the nine-year premium in one go,
then you can avail this maternity benefit
only after 9 months of taking the policy.
After that, the next add-on is newborn
baby cover. After taking this advance,
your newborn baby is covered up to twice the amount of your maternity claim.
And if we talk about vaccination of newborn baby, then
this is 1 per basic sum assured
whose maximum limit is ₹0,000 (first
year only). Next is Critical Illness
Advance. If you have taken this advance, then you
get a lump sum equal to your basic sum assured.
Its maximum limit is ₹50 lakh.
Next is Personal Accident Advance, which
works on all three - Death, Permanent Total Disability, and Permanent Partial Disability. You get its lump sum benefit as per
your subject, whose
maximum limit is ₹1 lakh. After this, the next
add-on is Sum Insured Protector.
After taking this add-on, your sum assured increases every year according to the
inflation rate.
After this, the next add-on is Claim
Protector. After taking this advance,
all your non-payable items, which are
also called consumer items, are also covered.
Friends, let us now
understand the waiting period in this plan. If we
talk about accident here, it is covered from day one.  The
initial waiting period is 30 days. The
waiting period for specific diseases is 2
years. Furthermore, the
waiting period for pre-existing diseases in this plan is also 2
years, compared to 4 years in most plans. The
waiting period for critical surgeries is
3 years. The
waiting period for maternity is nine
months. If you pay the premium for 3 years in one go, the
waiting period for critical illnesses is
60 or 90 days. The
survival period for critical illnesses is
zero days. Friends, I
hope you have understood this plan well.
If
you have any questions about this plan, you
can type your query in the comment box.
If you want to buy this plan or
want to buy the right health insurance plan for your family,
I would like to inform you that we
provide policies on an all-India basis
and also provide all related services. At the
time of claim, we
Jannali helps you, you can send us your family
size and everyone's date of birth by typing it in. The
links of our platform are also
given in the description box, you can follow us there as well
and lastly I request all of you to
like this YouTube video of ours and share it as much as possible. Also, do
not forget to turn on the notification bell so that you keep getting information about the upcoming
new plans and new videos.
Thank you very much for taking out your precious time and watching this video. See you soon
in the next video.
[Music]